Heat. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Heat
up here.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
[Applause]
Heat up here.
Heat.
[Applause]
Yeah.
Heat.
Amen. Amen. Amen. Happy Sabbath
everyone. Welcome again to Living Mana
Online Church.
And uh I am
uh so thankful
that uh that opening was almost three
minutes long. Why? because
uh we were having some technical issues
with my slides and uh just before it
ended my slides started to work. So,
praise God
uh not only for the powerful trailer but
also that the trailer was that long. All
right, y'all. We are going to get into
the word of God today. And this one is
going to be a study that is going to be
crucial
um for
a lot of Christians to understand.
There's a lot of talk going on right now
about Israel and and what should be how
should uh how should America and how
should Christians especially
um relate and respond to what's going
on. And today I'm going to be talking
about something that I think many people
miss
and I don't want to give it away at the
beginning. So we're just going to pray.
We're going to jump right into the
message which is called the Israel
America problem. You're going to want to
share this message
um with a lot of Christians. You're
going to want to share this message with
a lot of Christians. So, um share this
link now. Let people know that that this
message has begun and um
pay attention.
Take notes and listen carefully. Let's
pray. Heavenly Father, feed us today
Lord is our prayer in Jesus name. Open
our eyes that we may see. Amen. Amen.
Let's go to the screen.
The message is entitled the Israel
America problem. I want to start off
with a verse that is uh usually quoted
by Americans es or by Christians
especially here in America. It is Psalm
122 and verse 6 which says pray for the
peace of Jerusalem. They shall prosper
that love thee. they shall prosper that
love thee. And this verse has been taken
by many Christians to um to mean that
that
as Americans and as Christians, we we
ought to back uh Israel and support
Israel. And uh and so we pray,
Christians pray for the peace of Israel,
for the success of Israel. and and uh we
we want Christians often here,
especially here in America, want to find
themselves always supporting
Israel, but this verse needs context.
We've heard a lot of talk about context
in the last couple of weeks. This verse
needs context, and that's what we're
going to do. We're actually going to
build a and show God's relationship with
Israel. um beginning in the book of
Genesis. So, we're going to go on a
journey through the scriptures. Please
take notes and I need you to listen.
Absolutely. Listen very carefully. Let's
go to the screen. We're going to begin
with God's call to Abraham. It's found
in Genesis 12:1.
The Bible says, "Now the Lord had said
unto Abram, get thee out of thy country,
and from thy kindred, and from thy
father's house unto a land that I will
show thee." Verse 2 and three. And I
will make of thee a great nation, and I
will bless thee, and make thy name
great, and thou shalt be a blessing. and
I will bless them that bless thee, and
curse him that cursseeth thee, and in
thee shall all the families of the earth
be blessed. Let's read a little bit
further. Genesis chapter 13, God now
says this to Abraham. And the Lord said
unto Abram, after that Lot was separated
from him, lift up now thine eyes, and
look from the place where thou art
northward and southward, and eastward
and westward. For the land which thou
seest, to thee will I give it, and to
thy seed forever. And I will make thy
seed as a dust of the earth, so that if
a man can number the dust of the earth,
then shall thy seed also be numbered. I
want you to understand that here is the
introduction of the story of Abraham in
the Bible. God calls Abraham. God says,
"I'm going to make you a great nation."
He says, "I'm going to lead you into the
promise into a land of promise and those
that bless you, I will bless, and those
that curse you, I will curse." And
again, this is this is one of the verses
that is often used uh for Christians to
to take the position that that we ought
to pray and support Israel, right? A and
in whatever way that means, whatever
Israel does, we ought to be behind it.
And so as this story goes on in the
Bible, uh Abraham begins to have
children. He has uh um he has uh um
Isaac. Isaac has Jacob. Jacob has his 12
sons. And these 12 sons multiplied so
that by the time we get to the book of
Exodus
chapter 1 verse 7 we'll read and the
children of Israel were fruitful and
increased abundantly and multiplied and
waxed exceeding mighty and the land was
filled with them. Now there arose a new
king over Egypt which knew not Joseph.
And he said unto his people, "Behold,
the people of the children of Israel are
more and mightier than we. So you see
how numerous they were. Come on now, let
us deal wisely with them, lest they
multiply.
And it come to pass that when there
fallth out any war, they join also unto
our unto our enemies and fight against
us, and so get them up out of the land.
And the Lord So we'll pause right here.
Let's come back for a moment. So you can
see from Genesis 12 all the way up to
Exodus chapter 1, we now have the
children of Israel multiplied.
and and they're now in Egypt and Egypt
is about to to to to persecute them and
this is going to last for hundreds of
years. At the end of this time period,
this 400year time period, God calls a
man on the scene by the name of Moses.
And you will see God speaking to Moses
in Exodus chapter 3:8 where he says, "I
am come down now to deliver them out of
the hand of the Egyptians and to bring
them out of that up out of that land
onto a good land and a large a land
flowing with milk and honey and unto the
place of the Canaanites and the Hittites
and the Amorites and the Parizzites and
the Hivites and the Jebusites." So God
is now leading the children of Israel
out of Egypt and he's going to lead them
into the land that he promised to
Abraham.
If y'all are with me so far, put a one
in the chat. Put a one in the chat.
Pastor, we're following you. We've seen
the chronology. The children of Israel
are now about to enter the promised
land. And now we're going to see
something that is absolutely crucial
that many, many, many people miss. Let's
go back to the screen.
The children of Israel are about to
enter the promised land.
But before they do that, God calls
Joshua, who is the one that's going to
lead them into the promised land, to do
something. We read about this in Joshua
8:es 33 to35.
says here, "And all Israel and their
elders and officers and their judges
stood on this side of the ark and on
that side before the priests, the
Levites, which bear the ark of the
covenant, the Lord, a as well as a
stranger, as he that was born among
them, half of them over against Mount
Gerism, and half of them over against
Mount Ebal, as Moses, the servant of the
Lord, had had commanded before, that
they should bless the people of Israel.
And afterward he he read all the words
of the law. The blessings and cursings.
So I need you to put that in the chat
for me. There were blessings and
cursings according to all that is
written in the book of the law. There
was not a word of all that Moses
commanded which Joshua read not before
all the congregation of Israel with the
women and the little ones and the
strangers that were conversant among
them. So what's happening here is that
the children of Israel have now been
broken up into two companies. Six stand
on this co this mountain called the
mount of Jerisim which is where Joshua
was going to speak blessings and then
six tribes on Mount Ebal where Joshua
was going to speak curses. So you've got
these two mountains and this is before
they take possession of the land. And
let's see what this what these blessings
and what these cursings were about.
Let's go back to the screen and we're
going to read in Deuteronomy 28:1.
Here's what it says. And it shall come
to pass, if thou shalt hearken
diligently unto the voice of the Lord
thy God, to observe and to do all his
commandments, which I command thee this
day, that the Lord thy God will set thee
on high above all the nations of the
earth. And all these blessings shall
come upon thee, and overtake thee, if
thou hearken unto the voice of the Lord
thy God. There is a key word in this
verse. There is a key word in this
verse. Does anyone know what the key
word is?
Let me go back one verse earlier. What
is the key word here?
And it shall come to pass
if
if if
three times I'm saying the word just so
that you understand the significance. It
shall come to pass if so if Israel was
obedient then all these blessings would
overtake them. And so these blessings
start from from Deuteronomy 28:2 and
they go down to about verse 14. Then we
get to verse 15 and notice what it says
here.
But it shall come to pass,
if thou will not hearken unto the voice
of the Lord thy God, to observe to do
all his commandments, and his statutes,
which I command thee this day, that all
these curses shall come upon thee, and
shall overtake thee.
All right? So, what's happening here?
God is setting out conditions.
In other words, what God is saying is,
listen you guys,
what I'm about to tell you is
conditional. Put that word in the chat
for me, please. Conditional.
If A, then B. If C, then D. There are
conditions. And then just to amplify
this, notice what he says in Deuteronomy
30 19 and 20.
I call heaven and earth to record this
day against you that I have set before
you life and death, blessing and
cursing. Therefore,
choose life that thou mayest love the
Lord thy God, and that thou mayest obey
his voice. In other words, what God is
saying here, a and what the Bible is
telling us is God actually calls to
witness the entire world,
Israel,
if you obey my voice, I will bless you.
But if you do not obey my voice, you're
going to be cursed.
This is the Bible speaking. Not man, not
me, not you. This is God himself
speaking.
Now, I want you to notice what part of
the curse was in Leviticus 26:33 and and
34. He says this. This is this is the
chapter the chap the curses are
mentioned twice. Once in Deuteronomy 28,
once in Leviticus 26. Here's what it
says. I will scatter you among the
heathen, and will draw out a sword after
you, and your land shall be desolate,
and your cities waste. Then shall the
land enjoy her Sabbaths. As long as life
desolate, you shall be in your enemy's
land. And even then, and or even then
shall the land rest and enjoy her
Sabbaths. So again,
in Leviticus, God is telling the
children of Israel, if you don't obey
me, your land is going to end up
desolate, and you're going to end up
captives in another land. Everybody put
a one in the chat if you are following
so far. Put a one in the chat if you're
following so far. Now, Leviticus 26, the
same chapter, tells us something very
interesting.
From verse 40, it says this almost like
a clause in these curses. Right in the
midst of the curses, it says this.
If they shall confess their iniquities,
there's a key word here, everybody. What
is the key word in this verse? It is the
word if. If they shall confess their
iniquity and the iniquity of their
fathers with their trespass, which they
have trespassed against me, that also
they have walked contrary unto me, and
that I have also walked contrary unto
them, and have brought them into the
land of their enemies. If then their if
if if if if
then their uncircumcised hearts be
humbled, and they then accept of the
punishment of their iniquity, then will
I remember my covenant with Jacob, and
also my covenant with Isaac, and also my
covenant with Abraham, will I remember,
and I will remember the land. In other
words, I will deliver you out of the
land. All right. So, let's come back for
a moment and let's just recap that
according to God, the promises were
conditional.
Everybody put a five in the chat if you
see that thus far. Clearly, the promises
were conditional. Blessings if you if
you obey. Curses if you don't obey.
And even if you don't obey, but you
repent
back to back to a blessings again and I
will bring you back into the land.
So God was clearly showing them that
their
their salvation
was conditional.
as a nation.
Them being safe in the promised land,
them having peace and joy and happiness,
them
existing
without any issues
was conditional.
But Israel
adopted
a once saved, always saved position. In
other words, their position was look,
God blessed us and so it doesn't matter
what we do,
God has to bless us.
Y'all, y'all put a eight in the chat. I
want to make sure I'm using different
numbers so that I know you're following
the point that I'm making. There's a
little bit of lag. So, when I'm saying
put an eight, it's because I know you're
responding to the point I just made. So,
put an eight in the chat if you
understand. Israel adopted this
unconditional
salvation. This this unconditional once-
saved always saved attitude. Meaning,
hey, God is blessing us. And it doesn't
matter what we do. Doesn't matter how we
live. Doesn't matter how much we disobey
God. Doesn't matter how how nasty our
attitudes are. Doesn't matter how
corrupt we live our lives. God has to
bless us.
A and the Bible even tells us, notice
with me, Amos chapter 8 verse 9 verse
Amos chapter 9:es 8-10. Behold, the eyes
of the Lord God are upon the sinful
kingdom, and I will destroy it off the
face of the earth, saving, saving that I
will not utterly destroy the house of
Jacob, say the Lord. All the sinners of
my people shall die by the sword, which
say, "The evil shall not overtake nor
prevent us." In other words, listen to
me you guys.
Ancient Israel had this position that
because they were the children of
Abraham that God was bound to bless
them.
Once saved,
always saved. Doesn't matter what you
do. Once God has delivered you out of
Egypt, then that's it. Once God has
delivered you out of bondage, then there
is nothing. You cannot do anything to
lose your salvation. And if you can't do
anything to lose your salvation,
then really
you could live how you want to live,
do what you want to do,
and God still has to bless you.
So needless to say, this doctrine was a
false doctrine. This belief was a false
belief because God clearly said if if if
come with me to the screen. So notice
what happened. 2 Chronicles chapter
36:15 and 16. And the Lord God of their
fathers sent to them by his messengers
rising up at times and sending because
he had compassion on his people and on
his dwelling place. But they mocked the
messengers of God and despised his words
and misused misused his prophets until
the wrath of the Lord arose against his
people till there was no remedy.
Notice again with me Jeremiah 25:8-9.
Therefore thus sayith the Lord of hosts
because you have not heard my words
because you have not heard my words.
Behold, I will send and take all the
families of the north, sayeth the Lord,
and Nebuchadnezzar, the king of Babylon,
my servant, and will bring them against
this land, and against the inhabitants
thereof. Here is Jeremiah 25:11 and 12.
And this whole land shall be a
desolation and an astonishment. And
these nations shall serve the king of
Babylon 70 years. And it shall come to
pass when the 70 years are accomplished
that I will punish the king of Babylon
and that nation, sayith the Lord, for
their iniquity. Again, 2 Chronicles
36:21.
God here is speaking about the
Babylonian the the the Jerusalem going
into or the Jews going into Babylonian
captivity. He says to fulfill the word
of the Lord by the mouth of Jeremiah
even until the land had enjoyed her
Sabbaths. For as long as she lay
desolate, she kept Sabbath to fulfill
three score and 10 years. This is the
time period, the 70 years that they
spent in Babylon. Again, 2 Chronicles
36:19-20. They burnt the house of God
and break down the wall of Jerusalem,
and burnt all the palaces thereof with
fire, and destroyed all the goodly
vessels thereof. and them that had
escaped from the sword carried he away
to Babylon, where they were servants to
him and his sons until the reign of the
kingdom of Persia. So, let's pause for a
moment and let's just make sure we're
all in the same place. So, remember now,
Israel thought, hey, once saved, always
saved. God's not going to let anything
happened to us. We can do whatever we
want, live however we want, act however
we want, and God has to bless us because
we are his chosen people. But God said,
I said if. I didn't say this was
unconditional. I said if.
And as a result of them ignoring the if,
we might we might call this sermon
ignoring the if.
because they ignored the if and and went
along with this idea of once saved,
always saved, once saved. It doesn't
matter what you do, God is going to
bless you. So you could live how you
want to live, talk how you want to talk,
you know, act how you want to act. It
doesn't matter as long as you accept God
with your mouth, then you are good to
go. This is the philosophy that they
had.
And so they end up in Babylonian
captivity. If you're with me so far, put
a nine in the chat. Nine in the chat.
Pastor, we're following. We're with you
so far. They end up saying they end up
in Babylonian captivity because they
ignored the if they thought once saved,
always saved. Now, it is here in the
book of Daniel or here in Babylon that
we're introduced to a prophet named
Daniel.
And and this prophet Daniel in Daniel
chapter nine,
he's literally confessing the sins of
Israel almost verbatim quoting that they
that the curses that were spoken of in
Moses have been poured out upon them and
this is why they're in Babylonian
captivity. So he's confessing the sins
of Israel, confess confessing the sins
of the fathers. And there are probably
others doing this as well.
And as a result of this confession, an
angel comes to Daniel to give him a
prophecy.
Now, here is the prophecy. It is called
the 70 week prophecy. And we find it in
Daniel chapter 9 and verse 24.
This prophecy has been so largely
misunderstood by so many Christians that
it is this key prophecy that has the
Christian world basically in confusion
over Israel. So let's read this angel
comes to Daniel while he's praying and
the angel says this to Daniel. Daniel,
70 weeks are determined upon thy people
and upon thy holy city, to finish the
transgression, to make an end of sins,
to make reconciliation for iniquity, to
bring an everlasting righteousness, and
to seal up the vision and the prophecy,
and to anoint the most holy. Know
therefore, and understand that from the
going forth of the commandment to
restore, and to build Jerusalem unto the
Messiah, the prince, shall be seven
weeks, and three scoring, two weeks.
That's another way of saying 69
weeks.
Seven 70 weeks.
Of the 70 weeks, the 69 weeks would
bring you to the Messiah. That's what
the verse is saying. So, let's pause for
a second and we need to break something
down here. So this 70we prophecy,
the text just said that 69 of those
weeks will bring you to the Messiah.
Now, why is this important?
The children of Israel are in are in
Babylon because they have rejected God's
word. They have rejected the if the
conditional promises of God. They
thought once saved, always saved and now
here they are in Babylon. So
are they lost? Is this it? Has God
turned his back on his people? No. No,
no, no, no. He brings them this 70w week
prophecy.
And the 70we prophecy points to the
coming of the Messiah, which is the one
whom Israel must accept in order to
receive
the full forgiveness of God, mercy of
God, salvation of God. Y'all put a one
in the chat. Put a one in the chat
if you understand the point that I just
shared, especially if you've never heard
this before. you're you're you're a
Baptist, maybe you're a Pentecostal, and
maybe you've never understood this
prophecy. And if you're one of those,
I'm going to ask you to put a two in the
chat. If you're like, Pat, I'm getting
this, sir. I don't know who you are, but
hey, I'm getting this. This is making
sense. God is saying, "Listen, 69 weeks
from the beginning of this prophecy, and
we're not going to get into when that
prophecy began right now because that's
not the purpose of this study,
but 69 prophetic weeks will bring you to
the Messiah,
the one who is coming to die for your
sins, the one that is coming to give you
forgiveness."
Watch this. If you accept him, if if if
if
everybody if you accept him,
plan A, Mount Jerisim, the blessings. If
you reject him,
Mount Ebal, the curses. Do you all
understand?
Now, why is this 70we prophecy so
significant? Let me tell you why. Let's
let Jesus break it down for us. We're
going to go over, by the way, 70 weeks.
How many days in a week?
Seven days. So 70 weeks would be 70*
7. Does that number ring a bell?
Anybody? Does the number se does the
phrase 70* 7 ring a bell?
If it doesn't, let's find out why it
should ring a bell. If it does, you
might be like, "Where have I heard that
before?" Let's go to Jesus's own words.
Matthew chapter 18 verse 21 and 22. Then
came Peter to him and said, Lord, how
often shall my brother sin against me,
and I forgive him till seven times?
Jesus saith unto him, I say not unto
thee until seven times, but until 70
times seven. You guys,
the number the phrase 70* 7 is symbolic
of God's mercy.
70* 7.
That's that's the that's what that's
what's happening in this 490ear
prophecy. This 70we prophecy, it's the
same time period. 70 * 7 69 weeks brings
you down to the very one who is going to
offer you forgiveness and the remaining
70th week. The 70th week is your
opportunity to respond to the
forgiveness given to you.
Now, that 70th week, beloved,
we're going to see focuses around Jesus.
But hold on. Before we get there, we
need to finish seeing what Jesus says
right after Jesus says 70* 7, forgive
70* 7. Notice what he says. Let's go
back to the screen. So, watch this,
y'all. That's verse 22. Here comes verse
23.
Therefore is the kingdom of heaven
likened unto a certain king which would
take account of his servants. And when
he had begun to reckon, one was brought
unto him which owed him 10,000 talents.
But for as much as he had not to pay,
his lord commanded him to be sold and
his wife and his children, and all that
he had, and a payment to be made. The
servant therefore fell down and
worshiped him, saying, Lord, have
patience with me, and I will pay thee
all. Then the lord of that servant was
moved with compassion and the and loosed
him and forgave him the debt.
Let me ask you something everyone.
What was Jesus coming to do?
Jesus was coming to forgive the debt of
Israel.
And how is he going to do that? but
through his death, burial, and
resurrection.
And so in this parable that Jesus gives
right after he says 70* 7 and then he
says, "Hey, by the way, the kingdom of
heaven is like this."
It's like a man forgiving someone of
their debt. Israel, you're in debt right
now, aren't you? You're in Babylon.
You've not followed my ways. You've not
followed my my You've not followed my
word.
But don't worry Israel, I am coming to
grant you forgiveness.
And so when Jesus dies on the cross,
that is in in essence him forgiving the
debt for anyone who wants it. So now
watch this. The parallel continues.
Let's go back to the screen. Let's go
back to the screen.
So then it says,
Let's come back from the screen for a
moment. I I I'm saving this verse for
last.
So in the parable, we don't have it on
the screen. It actually continues that
the servant that was forgiven then goes
out and finds someone that owes him
money,
Gentiles.
the enemy, the Romans,
those that are not Israelites,
the wicked world. Y'all get the picture.
This man goes out and finds someone that
owes him money. And instead of him
offering what was offered to him at the
cross, instead of him offering that love
and that mercy and that forgiveness
because he was grateful for the
sacrifice made in his behalf, no, no,
no, no. He has an attitude towards the
Roman, towards the gentile, towards the
gay, I mean towards the gentile,
towards the heathen, towards the
unbeliever, that is not forgiving, that
is not merciful,
that doesn't say Jesus
to the non to the non
to the non-believers.
And so when when the Lord hears this,
now let's go to the screen. This guy
evidently thinks that once he's been
forgiven, he will always be forgiven.
That's how the parable goes. Hey, the
Lord forgave me the debt. I'm good to
go. I can treat people Letause for a
second, y'all. It It's time to preach.
It's time to preach.
I can treat people like dirt.
God has already forgiven me. So it
doesn't matter if I'm mean to you. It
doesn't matter if I talk this way to
you. It doesn't matter if if if I take
privilege away. It doesn't matter how I
treat you. I can put you where I can do
with you what I will. God has forgiven
me. Oh, God is love. Certainly. I love
the Lord and he loves me. He forgave me.
But extend mercy to you. Be kind to you.
Nah, you're the enemy. No, no, no, no,
no, no, no. You're a heathen. No, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no. You're a
you're a you're you're you're you're in
this party or that party. No, no, no,
no, no, no.
You don't believe what the Bible says.
Therefore, you are my enemy.
Why should I extend love, mercy,
patience, forbearance, understanding
with you?
And and I'm pretty secure in the way
that I'm treating you. Why? because
God's already forgiven me. It was a
tearful time. It was I I was filled with
tears as I accepted the love and the
grace and the mercy of God. It It was
such a move. You should have been there
at my baptism.
It was a beautiful experience.
And so in the parable, people oversee
people see how this forgiven man note
what I said y'all. Forgiven man is
treating others and they go back and
tell the Lord. And now watch what
happens. Let's go back to the screen.
Matthew 18:34 and 35. And his Lord was
wroth and delivered him to the
tormentors till he should pay all that
was due unto him. So likewise shall my
heavenly father do also unto you if you
if you from your hearts forgive not
everyone his brother his brother his
trespasses. You guys hold on. Let me I'm
going to read to you Matthew 18:32. Just
one two verses up. Then his lord, after
he had called him, said unto him, "Oh,
thou wicked servant, I forgave thee all
that debt because you desired of me,
should not you have also had compassion
on thy fellow servant, even as I had
pity on you?"
So Jesus is giving us a hint of what
this 70w week prophecy is about. What
he's saying to Israel is, "I am coming
to offer you forgiveness at the end of
these 69 weeks." Y'all get the picture?
How you respond to my sacrifice,
how you respond to what I did for you at
the cross, we're going to see the
prophecy actually says that will
determine whether you retain my blessing
or they are removed from you.
All right?
So, let's go back to the screen. Let's
go back to the screen. And here's what I
want you to see. So, this prophecy we
just read said 69 weeks will bring you
to the Messiah. For the sake of time,
I'm not going to talk about when this
prophecy begins. I'm simply going to
going to tell you the prophecy began in
457 BC. If you count 69 weeks or 483
years from the time that the decree went
forth to restore and build Jerusalem, as
we had just read a little bit earlier,
you come down to the very year of
Christ's baptism. Are y'all with me? You
come down to the very year of Christ's
baptism. Now, now, um, and here's, by
the way, if you want my slides, you'll
be able to get the slides, so don't
worry about it. Here it says this and
after three score in two weeks shamas be
cut off. Let me go back here. This means
sometime in the 70th week,
the final seven years,
the Messiah would be cut off. Now,
here's what this means, beloved. If the
Messiah would be cut off halfway
through that 70th year,
that 70th week, then it must means that
the 70 weeks occurred in the past when
Jesus was alive.
Y'all put a one in the chat if you
understand what I'm saying. Notice what
the text says. And after three score and
two weeks shall Messiah be cut off, but
not for himself. I get it, pastor. Jesus
died, was cut off, but he didn't die for
himself. He died for the world. That's
the sacrifice. Three and a half years
after Jesus's baptism, which is halfway
through that 70th week, Jesus is cut off
for us.
Here's what the text goes on to say.
and the people of the prince that shall
come shall destroy the city and the
sanctuary.
And the end thereof shall be with a
flood, and unto the end of the war
desolations are determined. So, let's
break this down. It's going to be a
little tedious, but don't worry, we're
going to juice it down and make it
simple. Who was the prince that was
going to be coming at the same time that
Jesus was crucified? We don't need to
guess. Jesus himself said in John
12:31-33,
"Now is the judgment of this world. Now
shall the prince
of this world be cast out." And then he
goes on to say, "And I, if I be lifted
up from the earth, will draw all men
unto me." This he said, signifying what
death he should die. In fact, y'all,
Jesus right before his death told his
disciples, "The prince of this world
cometh and has nothing in me." So, we
now know that Satan was that prince that
was going to be coming. In other words,
as it were, being cast, being locked out
of heaven at the death of Christ,
falling as it were,
having no more access as it were because
of the death of Jesus. That's why Jesus
said, "The prince of this world cometh
and has nothing in me. Now shall the
prince of this world be cast out." Okay?
So this is all happening at the cross.
Now I want you to notice with me Daniel
9 27. This is going to be the most
tedious part of this message. And again,
we're going to make it very simple, not
complicated at all. But listen to what
the text says. It now says, "And he
shall confirm the covenant with many for
one week. And in the midst of the week,
he shall cause the sacrifice and the
oblation to cease. And for the
overspreading of abominations, he shall
make it desolate, even until the
consummation, and that determined shall
be poured out upon the desolate. Now,
this verse, this one single verse has
thrown millions of Christians off on a
false trail. Let me break it down for
you.
Who was it that was to confirm the
covenant? It was Jesus. Jesus confirmed
the covenant. That's what he did at the
cross. Galatians 3:17. And this I say
that the covenant that was confirmed
before of God in Christ.
The law which is 400 years and 430 years
after cannot disenol that it should make
the promises of non- effect. Listen, the
covenant, Satan doesn't confirm a
covenant anywhere in the Bible. Nowhere
in the Bible do you find Satan
confirming a covenant. It is always God.
It is always Jesus. And the new covenant
was confirmed by Jesus. Jesus said in
Matthew 26:28, "This is my blood of the
new testament which is shed for many for
the remission of sins." Remember, watch
this. Let's go back. Let's go back. And
he shall confirm the covenant with many
for one week. Let's go back. Jesus said,
"This is my blood." The blood of the new
testament or new covenant which is shed
for many. For what? For the remission of
sins. Let's keep going. The Bible says,
"For it is not possible that the blood
of bulls and goats should take away
should take away sins." Meaning Christ's
death brought an end to the sacrificial
system.
Are y'all with me?
Christ's death put an end to the
sacrificial system. That's what Daniel 9
is talking about when it says
when it says that he would put an end to
the sacrifices.
This is all fulfilled in Christ back
there at the cross. Now watch this you
guys.
In Jesus's days, the Jews had adopted
again the once-s saved, always saved,
unconditional
blessings of God. We are Abraham's seed
and it doesn't matter what we do,
God is going to bless us. And Jesus had
to check them on that continually. For
example, here is John speaking. Here is
John speaking in Matthew 3:7-9. But when
he saw many of the Pharisees and
Sadducees come to his baptism, he said
unto them, "Oh generation of vipers, who
has warned you to flee from the wrath to
come? Bring forth fruits meet for
repentance, and think not to say within
yourselves, we have Abraham to our
father. For I say unto you that God is
able of these stones to raise up
children to Abra." God can create
children of Abraham. Don't think that
just because you are the bloodline of
Abraham that that carries any
significance at all with God. If you are
not bringing forth fruit meet for
repentance, do not deceive yourself.
How about Jesus's own words? That was
John. Here's Jesus. Then said Jesus to
those Jews which believed on him. Now
notice how it notice how it qualifies.
Then said Jesus to those Jews which
believed on him,
"If you continue in my word, then are
you my disciples indeed." So not all the
Jews were Jesus's disciples, only the
ones that believed in his word, and you
shall know the truth, and the truth
shall make you free." They answered him,
"We be Abraham's seed, and we were never
in bondage to any h to any man. How
sayest thou, you shall be made free?" So
now these are the other Jews that are
talking. Jesus says, "I know that you
are Abraham's seed, but you seek to kill
me because my word has no place in you.
I speak that which I have seen with my
father, and you do that which you have
seen with your father." Wow, how
offensive, they think to themselves.
They answered and said unto him, Abraham
is our father. And now notice what Jesus
says. If you were Abraham's children.
Wait, what?
If? What do you mean if Jesus? I mean,
that's a pretty like uh weird statement.
What do you mean if? There's no if.
We're all Abraham's children. They're
saying, "What are you talking about?"
But no, no, no. Jesus says,
"If
you were Abraham's children, you would
do the works of Abraham. But now you
seek to kill me, a man which has told
you the truth, which I have heard of
God. This did not Abraham. You do the
deeds of your father." Then they said to
him, "We not we be not born of
fornication. We have one father, even
God."
Jesus says, "Why do you not understand
my speech, even because you cannot hear
my word? You are of your father, the
devil, and the lust of your father you
will do." Now, pause for a second,
y'all.
What is Jesus saying here? Jesus himself
is saying
it doesn't matter if you were born of
Abraham.
If you reject the Messiah,
you're not Abraham's seed in God's eyes.
You cannot claim Abraham
and yet be seeking to kill me.
This thing is conditional, y'all. Your
salvation is conditional upon me.
And so we know what happened, right?
Israel as a nation, not everyone, but as
a nation, Israel rejects the Messiah.
They crucify him.
They reject his teachings. Not all
because we find on the day of Pentecost,
the Bible says there there appeared unto
them clothed in tongues like as a fire
which sat upon them and they were all
filled with the Holy Ghost and began to
speak with other tongues as the spirit
gave them utterance. And there were
dwelling at Jerusalem Jews, devout men
out of every nation under heaven. So
there are Jews that are now under the
influence of accepting Christ and of
receiving the spirit. The early church
was made up of Jews. Y'all put a five in
the chat if you're following. So now I
want you to see what we've just seen
creates a distinction between spiritual
Israel, those that have accepted Christ,
those that have been born again. They're
still literal Jews, but they are
spiritual Israel. And God is saying,
"Now there's another group of people who
are literal Jews, but that's all they
are. They are just lit. They're just
Abraham's offspring,
but they're not a part of the promise
that only comes through accepting the
seed.
And so Jesus could say stuff like this.
Notice with me, Luke 13:34, "Oh
Jerusalem, Jerusalem, which killth the
prophets, and stoneth them that are sent
unto thee. How often would I have
gathered thy children together, as a hen
doth gather her brood under her wings,
and ye would not? Behold, your house is
left unto you desolate. Let me go back,
stay on the screen. Let me just run back
here real quick to that Daniel chapter 9
where it says, let's read it again. and
for the overspreading of abominations.
He that is Jesus shall make it desolate
even until the consummation meaning even
until the end of time when that
determined shall be poured out upon the
desolate. We're talking about the
plagues. Jesus himself says as he's
about to be crucified as he leaves
Jerusalem for the last time says your
house is left unto you desolate. You
will not see me again until the second
coming, the consummation, when that
poured out upon the desolate will be
poured out. Jesus was saying, "Nation of
Israel, because as a nation you have
rejected me,
your house is left unto you desolate.
You've chosen Mount Ebal.
You've rejected Jerism. You've rejected
the blessings. You've rejected following
me. You've rejected my offer of
forgiveness.
You're not willing to extend mercy,
grace. You're not willing to extend what
I've extended to you to the Romans, to
the LGBTQ, I'm sorry, to the Romans, to
the unbeliever. You're not willing to
show them mercy. You're not willing to
treat them the way I treated you.
And so after the 70* 70 is complete,
we know that Jerusalem
gets destroyed.
The temple gets destroyed.
And now it doesn't matter if Israel were
to come back 20 years, 50 years, 80
years later and rebuild a temple and do
all those things without accepting
Jesus. The promise is null and void. Put
a five in the chat if you're following
me.
Because the if was still this
if my people repent and confess their
sins. So they could have said, "Hey,
we're not we're not we're still not
going to accept Jesus, but you know
what? We want to rebuild our temple. We
want to rebuild our city." They could
have done all that and still
This is Eore.
You are now like any other nation on the
planet, my people. In fact, let me let's
let Jesus say it. Let's let Jesus say
it. In Matthew 21:43, Jesus said this,
"Therefore, I say unto you, the kingdom
of God shall be taken from you and given
to a nation bringing forth the fruits
thereof. And whosoever shall fall on the
stone shall be broken, but on whom it
shall fall, it will grind him to
powder." And when the chief priests and
Pharisees had heard his parables, they
perceived that he spake of them and they
sought to lay it made them pretty angry,
but they feared the multitude because
they took him for a profit.
Let's see,
does Paul bring this principle,
highlight this principle? He sure does.
Let's go over to Romans chapter 2 verse
29 to and to uh 31.
Paul himself says this,
"But he is a Jew." In fact, I need to
start with verse 30, and I'll go into
verse 31. Verse 30 says this, "For he is
not a Jew, which is one outwardly,
neither is circumcision that of the
heart, or that which is outward in the
flesh.
But he is a Jew, which is one inwardly.
And circumcision is that of the heart,
in the spirit, and not in the letter,
whose praise is not of men, but of God.
Did y'all see this?
I get you, Kevin. I'm coming there.
Please understand. extending mercy and
grace to the drunkard, to the to the
prostitute, to the homosexual. That God
is not saying, "Hey, tell the drunkard
and the and the prostitute, tell the
people that are living this way that
it's cool and it doesn't matter." That's
not what that's not what mercy is.
That's not what love is.
It's simply treating those who don't
understand, those who maybe even reject.
Those who nailed Jesus to the cross,
Jesus said, "Father, forgive them for
they know not what they do.
It is extending
love despite people seeing it
differently than you.
That's what Jesus has called the
follower of himself of Christians of
Christ to do.
So come come. Jesus now says listen
don't get locked up on the outward
appearance. Oh, you're a blood
descendant. No, no, no, no. That's not
the Jew. the the the biblical the
spiritual Israelite is the one that I'm
concern is the one that is a follower of
me. That's one that's me. That's what
I'm looking at.
Let's look at it again. Galatians 3 29.
And if you be Christ, then are you
Abraham's seed jaw and hes according to
the promise. How how what context do you
need to understand that what Paul just
said is that if you have accepted Christ
that makes you a seed of Abraham and if
you are a seed of Abraham that makes you
an Israelite.
No, not an Israelite after the flesh.
you just become a Jamaican Israelite
or a Hispanic Israelite
or a Jewish Israelite
because God is not concerned about
literal bloodline. He's concerned about
spiritual bloodline. Who has the blood
of Jesus flowing through their veins?
That's the connection he's looking for.
Hey, are you related to Jesus? Yeah, I
was born again. You're Abraham's seed.
That's why Abraham's seed is going to be
a great multitude of all nations. Not of
one nation, of all. In these shall all
the families of the earth be blessed.
And how do you get in Abraham? You have
to get in Christ. If you're in Christ,
then are you Abraham's seed and hes
according to the promise. So then we can
now begin to understand why Colossians
2:11 says, "In whom ye also you are
circumcised with the circumcision made
without hands in the putting off of the
body of the sins of the flesh by the
circumcision of Christ." It's no longer
literal circumcision that Gentiles had
to do in order to become an Israelite in
the Old Testament. No, now it's
spiritual
circumcision. Those who have received
Jesus in the heart, you are now an
Israelite.
Now watch what Paul says you guys in
Romans 9:6. He says, "Not as though the
word of God has taken on effect, for
they are not Israel which are of
Israel." Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow.
They are not all Israel which are of
Israel. In other words, what he's saying
is
you can actually be a physical
Israelite, but that's not what counts
with God. What counts with God is if
you're a spiritual Israelite. And only
spiritual Israelites will be saved. In
order to be saved, you must be an
Israelite. The covenant is made only
with Israel.
So now we got a problem. Because if
you're not Israel, you're not saved.
Therefore,
if everybody if if there are going to be
people of every nation, kindred, tongue,
and people that are saved, it means that
Israel grew to encompass every nation,
kindred, and tongue.
Everyone, anyone who says, "Lord, I want
you in my heart. I accept you, and I'm
going to live how you lived. I'm going
to live out your principles in my life.
You are Abraham's seed.
This is how third angel, you get into
Abraham's bosom. I love that.
So then, so then now watch this you guys
because I was going somewhere with this.
Listen carefully. Let's go back to the
opening text. When the text says, "Pray
for the peace of Jerusalem. They that
prosper, they shall prosper that love
thee."
Christians today think God is talking
about literal Jerusalem that was left
desolate
back in 70 AD.
They think, "Oh, so that means that
whatever Israel does, we've got to
support Israel." But beloved, you what
you have to understand is that in the
New Testament in Christ, these things
become spiritual. In the book of
Revelation, Babylon is not a literal
place. It is a spiritual place
representing all the wicked. And there
are only two powers at the end of time.
There is Babylon and there is Jerusalem.
There is Babylon and there is Israel.
If you're not in Israel, you're in
Babylon. And you could live in Mexico
and be in Babylon. You could be in
Australia and be in Babylon. You could
be in in in Taiwan and be in Babylon. As
well as you could live in America and be
an Israelite. You could live in Africa
and be an Israelite. You could live in
Spain and be Listen y'all,
spiritual things are spiritually
discerned.
So then this idea
that that Israel is supposed to be
supported leads to something very very
dangerous. In fact, it leads to the same
mistake Israel of the Old Testament made
when they thought once saved, always
saved. When they thought it doesn't
matter what we do,
God has said he's going to bless us. No
conditions. We We skip that part. It
leads to something. And I need you to
pay close attention, y'all. I need you
to understand. So, Israel made that
mistake. And now we're dealing with the
church. And I'm going to tell you,
beloved, that the church ends up making
the same mistake as well. Watch this,
y'all. So, around 320
something AD, around 320 something AD,
just leave it. We're not going to go to
the screen yet. Um, there was a man that
came on the scene by the name of
Constantine.
And Constantine
uh became converted to Christianity. Now
mind you, Christians had been be were
being persecuted by the Roman armies, by
the Roman Empire, and they suffered for
hundreds of years. And when Constantine
converted,
most scholars agree that it was a
nominal conversion, meaning it wasn't
real.
It it was it was for the purposes of
political gain.
And the church instead of following
Christ's principle of Christianity is
not about outward acceptance. Hey, I
accept Jesus and I can still kill
people. I can still kill my family.
Which is what Constantine did.
They were like, "Oh, he says he's a
Christian. Let's go. We're good to go.
He's going to give us political power.
He's going to exalt Christianity in the
nation. Man, this is just what we
wanted." And what happens is this is the
forerunner of what became known as dark
age Christianity where Christians were
persecuting so-called Christians were
persecuting others who didn't believe as
they believed. And watch this. It was
because they had gotten into the same
idea of righteousness by name. Hey,
I'm a I'm a child of Abraham. God is
blessing me. So it doesn't matter what I
do. It doesn't matter that we're burning
people at the stake. We are still
Christians.
It doesn't matter that we're burning
people at the stake who who we find with
a Bible in their possession. We're still
Christians. And guess what? We can be
Christians and do this. God once saved,
always saved.
We're good to go.
And this is basically how you can
describe the Christianity of the dark
ages. It was hypocrisy. It was history
repeating itself.
In the book Great Controversy, page 49,
the author says, "The nominal conversion
of Constantine in the early part of the
4th century caused great rejoicing,
great rejoicing by Christians
and the world clothed with a form of
righteousness walked into the church
like there was a great revival. People
were like, "Yes, Constantine." And and
thousands flocked into the churches and
people celebrated it.
But the author says, "Now the work of
corruption rapidly progressed. Paganism
while appearing to be vanquished became
the conqueror. Her spirit controlled the
church. Her doctrines, ceremonies, and
superstitions were incorporated into the
faith into the faith and worship of the
professed followers of Christ.
Righteousness by name. All you had to do
was confess Jesus with your mouth. And
then it didn't matter. It didn't matter
what you did. It didn't matter how you
lived.
As long as you accepted Christ,
you were considered good to go.
Now, we need to get down to our day,
y'all. So, so
forgive me. And I know this message is I
know there's a lot in this message, but
we're about to get to the main. If you
thought we hadn't gotten to the main
point, we're about to get to the main
point right now, you guys. We're about
to get to the main point.
So, in the 1830s,
there was a man by the name of uh John
Nelson Darby.
And I'mma just read John Nelson Darby.
um
brought a a particular new teaching into
Christianity. So Irish Plymouth Brethren
uh founder John Nelson Darby
revolutionized Protestant esquetology
with his dispensational dispensational
premillennial sharp sharply
premillennialism sorry sharply dividing
biblical history into seven distinct
eras where God's dealing with humanity
shift. So there was for example law for
Israel, grace for the church culminating
in a secret pre-tribulation rapture and
futuristic antichrist interpretation
that sideline the papacy's historic role
Daniel 7 as the little horn of Bible
prophecy.
So, let's pause for a second and and
just come back for a moment because what
I want you to understand here is that it
was this teaching that actually went
back to the to the 70th week of Daniel
chapter 9 that we read that was
fulfilled in Jesus and said, "No, we're
going to separate that 70th week from
the 69 and put it into the future." So
that the teaching now said that in the
future,
the antichrist is going to go to Israel
and make a covenant with them for seven
years. In the midst of that seven years,
he's going to cut off the covenant or
stop the covenant,
break the covenant, and and this is when
the antichrist will be revealed.
By the way, the church will be raptured
away before any of this happens.
And this points to that teaching of the
rapture. Remember a couple of days ago
how people thought the rapture well all
of this is from that particular
teaching.
So So I want you to notice something in
in in this new teaching which now has
been adopted by almost every major
Christian movement in America. The 70th
week is no longer no longer applied to
Jesus in the past. Takes away the whole
meaning of Jesus giving the whole
meaning Jesus gave to that prophecy.
Israel, your salvation as a nation is
now dependent on how you accept or
reject me. It brought in this teaching
called the rapture or popularized it.
And it taught that l Israel was literal
and would be restored to the land. And
when this restoration of the land
happened, that was a sign
that God was on the move.
No repentance needed, no accepting Jesus
needed, just Israel is going to uh to be
restored. And that is God in action. And
it also taught that in this dis
dispensation that the law of God was not
necessary. That was for the Jews.
And so when in 1948,
the Jewish state was reinstated,
Protestants in America was like, "Oh,
this is it. We're disp we're
dispensationalist all the way. This is
evidence that that God is on the move."
That pro. But what happened beloved?
What they did not do is take into
consideration
the Bible.
Listen to this. Now this is from the
Skullfield Bible which was written in 19
I believe it was 1911 or 1909 somewhere
around there which was based on this
principle which is where all the
teaching spiraled like it just just like
went rapid in America. And I want you to
notice what what Scoffield's notes say
based on this teaching.
The Christian is not under the Mosaic
covenant of works, the law, but under
the unconditional
unconditional
new covenant of grace. Y'all see that
word there?
Once saved,
always saved.
And by the way, you don't need to keep
the law of God.
It this popularized
this idea. It's not in my let let me
just read it. This popularized this idea
in Romans 10:9 that that where it says
if thou shalt confess with thy mouth the
Lord Jesus and shall believe in thine
heart that God has raised from the dead,
thou shalt be saved. So that for for
millions of Christians, it just became,
hey, all I got to do is confess Jesus
with my mouth and then I'm good to go.
It doesn't matter if I now hate my
political enemy. It doesn't matter if I
hate the Marxists or it doesn't matter
if I hate these people in the name of
Jesus. I've already been forgiven. So, I
can actually do what I want to do. Have
a spirit of anger, of hatred. And by the
way, by the way,
this totally bypasses
first John chapter 2:4, which says, "He
that saith, I know him and keepeth not
his commandments is a liar, and the
truth is not in him." There's a balance
there. You can't just say, "Hey, I
accepted Jesus in my life 20 years ago
or five years ago at a stadium. I said,
"I accept you, Jesus, and now I'm good
to go. I don't have to keep his
commandments. I don't No. The text says,
"He who says I know him and does not
live out the commandments is a liar and
the truth is not in him." So, let me
break it down for you. Now, we're about
to pull this whole thing together. You
see, when Christians look at Israel,
modern day Israel, and see Israel doing
things that ah may not I can't justify
that righteously, but God said pray for
Israel. What that does is this. Hey, if
Israel can do these things that may not
be the best, may not look that good, may
be like outright like, whoa, what is but
God still accepts them because they're
his people.
Then that changes my picture of who God
is.
Now, God is a God who doesn't mind
if you're blowing up
children.
I mean, if it happens, I mean, yeah,
it's kind of bad, but we got to pray for
Israel.
God doesn't mind
if Israel acts like any other nation.
Corruption is in every nation. There's
nothing different about Israel.
Every nation is corrupt. Every nation
has corruption. But in the mind of the
Christian, while God favors that nation,
so it must be okay then to I if Israel
can do these things and have God's
unconditional protection and we also are
to say blindly, yes, we love it's right,
but hey, it doesn't matter. The Bible
says pray for Israel and bless Israel no
matter what they do. Then I'm just going
to do it. And what this does, beloved,
is it trains the Christian to then
subtly make that shift that, hey, if
Israel, the nation, can do these things
and still be of God, then
maybe I can hate my political enemies.
I can hate those who are against
Christians.
I can hate the secularists. I can I can
I can demonize.
Y'all catch what I'm saying?
And so now in the in the in the
Christian mind,
there's no more contradiction
of
looking like a lamb but acting like a
dragon.
It's not a contradiction. It's okay.
Look at Israel.
So now you can have someone stand up in
front of mil thousands millions of
people and say, "Hey, I hate my enemies
and I don't want to forgive them." And
Christians be like, "That's I mean, you
know, it's but
God is for us."
We can have you can
you can have open corruption and yet
still say but this is Christian. You can
have the spirit of anger and yet still
say but yeah it's Jesus though. And and
as long as we have Jesus our corruption
and our anger and our vitrial and our we
can be angry at the people and we can do
all those things but we're accepted of
God.
And what begins to happen is you begin
to get this concept of righteousness by
name. As long as I say I'm a Christian
and beloved, this is what is happening
in Christianity today.
All because of this misunderstanding
of God's relationship with Israel.
You see,
the Bible tells us this. It says, "Know
this also that in the last days perilous
time shall come. For men shall be lovers
of their own selves, covetous, boasters,
proud, blasphemers, disobedient to
parents, unthankful, unholy, traitors,
heady, high-minded, lovers of pleasure,
more than lovers of God, having a form
of godliness." We're not talking about
the unbeliever here. A lot of Christians
vote the A lot of Christians take this
verse and say this is the unbeliever.
No. The text says having a form of
godliness, claiming to be Christians and
yet having the same spirit of the world,
having the same anger as the world,
having the same vitrial as the world.
Beloved, this righteousness by name, as
long as I accepted Jesus with my mouth
and said I believe him in my heart, that
that makes me a Christian, is a doctrine
of demons.
It is a doctrine of demons.
It is not truth. So when Jesus says pray
for Israel, listen y'all, go with me to
the screen. The Bible says, "Husbands,
love your wives even as Christ loved the
church and gave himself for it." The
church is is symbolically a woman. When
the Bible says in Revelation 12:17, "The
dragon was wroth with the woman." He's
talking about the church,
God's church, Christ church, Christ's
bride. And notice how the church is
described. The dragon was wroth with the
woman and went to make war with the
remnant of her seed which do what?
Have Abraham's blood? No. Which keep the
commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus.
That's the church, you guys. That is
Israel today. And Israel today, beloved,
is made up of Jews
who are Jews of the flesh and Gentiles
who are spiritual Israelites.
That's what the church is. That's what
the church is made up of.
And because so many Christians don't
understand this, they're over here
praying for a nation that is a secular
nation.
And that's okay.
But now we begin to say, "Wait a minute.
So these people, this nation doesn't
accept Christ, but we're still going to
treat them as if they accepted Christ."
And God's blessing is upon them even
though as a nation they're like, "No,
no, Jesus." How does that work? And if
that contradiction works, then you
understand, okay, well then, hey, you
know, I'm doing better. I accept Jesus
with my mouth,
but it's all right. I still hate my
enemies. And I and I take pleasure when
I see others hating on my enemies. My
side. Yes. Come on. Christian side. We
got to defeat our enemies, which is the
spirit of Satan, y'all.
Revelation 13:11, the Bible says, "I
beheld another beast coming up out of
the earth, and he had two horns like a
lamb and spake as a dragon." We're not
going to talk about who this power is.
I'm simply going to say that this is the
perfect description of what it means to
have the outward appearance
of a lamb, of a Christian, but speak
like a dragon.
Listen.
Listen,
Titus 1:6 says this, "They profess that
they know God, but in their works they
deny him, being abominable and
disobedient, and unto every good work
repbate."
Y'all got to understand, beloved, God
doesn't care about your profession. God
doesn't care that you said with your
mouth, "Oh, yeah, I accepted Christ."
and still have hate for your enemy,
still have hate for your brother in the
church, still have hate. God does not
care about that.
We need to understand this very,
very closely, y'all, because the world
is pushing a Christianity that simply
says once you accept Christ, that's all
you need.
You're good to go. Listen,
Jesus said these words in Matthew
Matthew 15:9. This people drawth nigh
unto me with their mouth and honorth me
with their lips, but their heart is far
from me. In vain do they worship me,
teaching for doctrines the commandments
of men. Jesus doesn't care about what
you say. He cares about what you do.
Jesus doesn't care about your profession
if your profession of Christ doesn't
match with your works,
with your actions, with your attitudes.
Isaiah 29:13, "Wherefore the Lord saith,
for as much as this people draw near
with me with their mouth, and with their
lips do honor me, but have removed their
hearts from me, and their fear toward me
is taught by the precepts of men."
man is telling you, "Hey, as long as you
are anti-abortion,
it doesn't matter if you're killing
people with your words, if you're
killing people with your attitude, it
doesn't matter if you hate. As long as
you got the right positions, you're good
to go. You're a follower of Jesus. Yes,
you got the right position, check.
Anti-abortion, check.
Anti- anti-gay, check."
as if the checklist of what you're anti
makes you a follower of Jesus.
But because we believe that God blesses
people unconditionally, that there's no
condition to salvation, then you can see
in people's minds, it doesn't matter how
you act. You can act like the devil and
at the same time be like, I'm a follow
Jesus. That's why you could say demonic
things, devilish things, and people
still say, "Oh, yeah, but that's
Christian."
Yeah. You just got to understand what
the devil means when he says that.
And you have all kinds of people
claiming Christianity who are saying all
kinds of things designed to provoke
design. What? You said what? You said
what? And you could be like, "Yeah,
yeah, what? What's the matter?"
righteousness
by name.
The Bible says in Ecclesiastes 12:13 and
14, let us hear the conclusion of the
whole matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments, for this is the whole duty
of man, for for God shall bring every
work into judgment with every secret
thing, whether it be good or whether it
be evil. God is not going to judge. Did
you say I accept Jesus? That's not what
he's judging. He's judging every secret
work. And so if your secret work if your
secret work does not match with what
your words say
more so
your words can already condemn you.
So if your words are right but your
actions are wrong then that's one thing.
If your words are already wrong, that's
already it.
The battle for Jesus has never been over
a nation. It has always been the battle
of the heart. And this is the problem
with modern day Christianity.
We're fighting.
Christians are fighting for the nation.
This nation is not God's nation.
God doesn't have a nation.
God's nation is in heaven.
That's his nation.
and and and God said, "If my kingdom
were of this world, then would my
servants fight."
This is not to say that we should want
the best for this nation or any nation
that we live in and do our part to help
that nation be the best place it can be.
But beloved, the battle is not for the
nation. The battle, the promised land
that God is looking for is not the
nation. This is the promised land that
God is fighting for. It's the promised
land of the heart.
Jeremiah 31:33, note with me on the
screen, but this shall be the covenant
that I will make with the house of
Israel. The covenant, beloved, is made
only with the house of Israel. Meaning,
if you can't find a way to become part
of the house of Israel, you're in
trouble. And the only way to become the
part part of the house of Israel is to
be born again. And the only way that you
could do that is through Jesus. Jesus is
your doorway into the covenant.
After those days, sayith the Lord, I
will put my law in their inward parts
and write it in their hearts and will be
their God, and they shall be my people.
So, here's the hypocrisy, beloved.
Here's the hypocrisy here. Here it is
again in Hebrews 8:10. For this is the
covenant that I will make with the house
of Israel after those days, sayeth the
Lord. I will put my laws in their mind
and write them in their hearts and I
will be to them a God and they shall be
to me a people. The same Christians in
this nation that are that are saying we
don't need a law of God. We're not under
the law. The law has been done away
with. Turn around and say we demand the
law of God in our schools.
The Ten Commandments should be placed in
our schools and in our governments and
we should live by those commandments.
The nation should live by those
commandments. But when someone says,
"Hey, those laws need to be written on
your heart." You're like, "No, on the
heart, no, I'm not under the law." How
can you at the same time be not under
the law and then at the same time
rejoice when the Ten Commandments are
put in schools?
If we're not under the law, why you want
the Ten Commandments in our schools?
See, that's legalism. That's legalism.
Legalism is looking for legal ways to
implement your belief on others. We're
going to use the law government to
enforce our view of Christianity.
We're even going to use the law NSPM7
if you haven't heard of it, which now
says anyone who speaks against
Christianity can now be investigated
for a crime.
So if you're not speaking my language of
Christianity, you can get in trouble
with the law.
And one day, beloved, the things that
you've heard today will be considered
hate speech
against the modern-day popular version
of Christianity, which is a
righteousness by name Christianity only.
So, as long as I'm singing and I'm
crying and I say Jesus and I have the
right checkpoints, but I I but I can
still talk like a dragon and I can still
hate my enemies. Yeah, y'all don't know.
Look it up. NPM-7
September 25th. That is the day that it
was released. Google it.
The hypocrisy is that
when someone comes and says, "Hey, the
law of God should be kept in the heart.
Oh, that's legalism. You're depending on
the law to be saved." No, no, no, no,
no, no. But at the same time, you're
going to turn around and say
the law should be in our schools. The
same law that I just said has been done
away with at the cross. That law should
be in our schools. That's legalism. That
is legalism. And it is the hypocrisy of
modern day Christianity.
It is the hypocrisy of modern day
Christianity. The battle for the
Christian, beloved, is not over the
nation. It is over the heart. Jeremiah
17:9. We're closing. Jeremiah 17:9.
Verse 9. The Bible says, "The heart is
deceitful above all things and
desperately wicked. Who can know it?
Romans 7:23, "But I see another law in
my members, waring against the law of my
mind, and bringing me into captivity to
the law of sin which is in my members."
Beloved, when you understand the law,
the warfare that is going on in your own
flesh, you do not have time to hate
other people because you got a greater
battle ahead of you, which is this, your
flesh,
self.
You ought to hate self and nobody else.
I hate one person and that's self. But
the devil has you hating in the name of
Jesus. I hate them. I hate them.
I hate them.
And I'm a Christian, too.
How can we get them? How can we destroy
them? Cuz they're just going too far
now. We got to put an end to this. We've
got to save the West. Really Jesus is
concerned about the west and not the
east or the north or the south. Really?
Jesus battle at the end of time is over
the west. Where do you get that in the
Bible? Where do we get that in
Christianity? Where do we get Jesus
saying fight for the west? Because if
the west goes then all my cards are out.
There's nothing else I can do. So I need
you all, my church, to fight for the
west.
Galatians 5:17, for the flesh lustth
against the spirit, and the spirit
against the flesh, and these are
contrary one to another to another, so
that you cannot do the things that you
would. The battle that God has called us
to fight is the battle against the
flesh, not the battle against the
nation. Luke 6:45, "A good man out of
the good treasure of his heart bringeth
forth that which is good, and an evil
man out of the evil treasure of his
heart bringeth forth that which is evil.
For out of the abundance of the heart,
the mouth speaketh. The battle is not
against the nation. The battle is not
for the nation. The battle is for the
heart. The heart is the promised land
that God is trying to conquer in you.
Two more verses and we're done.
2 Corinthians 10:4 says, "For the
weapons of our warfare are not carnal,
but mighty through God to the pulling
down of strongholds." In other words,
beloved, we don't wrestle against flesh
and blood. And I hear Christians using
this verse today, pointing to flesh and
blood, saying, "Hey, we don't wrestle
against flesh and blood, but look at the
flesh and blood. They are our enemies.
They're demonpossessed, and we've got to
do what we can through the government to
get rid of them, to stop them before we
lose the West." What in the world? Show
me the West in the Bible.
What warfare? Jesus called us to fight.
Cultural wars
with
non-believers.
That's the battle.
See,
most Christians have no idea. They many
Christians believe that the great
controversy is a cultural war.
And if you're hearing this for the first
time, I want to encourage you that there
is a great controversy and it is not
over cultural wars. The great
controversy runs much deeper.
And I wish
I wish that more Christians were aware
of this thing called the great
controversy,
the real battle between Satan and Jesus
and what's really on the table.
It is a battle over hearts and minds,
not over nations and kingdoms.
This is why Psalm 51:10, our last verse,
and I got a quote I want to read you.
Says, "Create in me a clean heart, oh
God, and renew a right spirit within me.
Not create a new nation
in America.
Create in me a clean heart, oh God, and
renew a right spirit within me." Let me
tell you something.
The world is looking at Christianity
today and saying, "What a mockery."
I don't know God,
but from what I know about Jesus, he
definitely wasn't like what I'm seeing
right now.
And it's all the more reason that I
don't believe Jesus existed. All the
more reason I don't believe that that
that the Bible is real, that God, that
there's a God. Because if he was real,
at least I would expect to see Christ
likeness
in the people that claim to be following
Jesus.
But I do not see Christlikkeness.
And when I see the people who claim to
be following Jesus, accepting others as
Christians who I can clearly see do not
look like Jesus to me, do not talk like
Jesus to me, do not act like Jesus to
me, do not have the temperament of Jesus
to me, then you just confirm why I
believe that the whole Bible is a sham,
that Christianity is just a madeup
religion, because you eyes are mocking
are are a mockery to the very thing you
say you believe.
And what a shame for Christians to not
reflect the one whom they say they
follow.
If Jesus were here today, he would not
be allowed in many of the Christian
churches because of his positions.
They'd be like, "Get out.
We don't want you as Jesus. We want
another Jesus. We want a Jesus that's
going to affirm us
in what we think.
My closing statement and we're going to
pray. It's from the book The Desire of
Ages, page 309. And it says this, "The
greatest deception of the human mind in
Christ's day was that a mere ascent to
the truth constitutes righteousness. In
all human experience, a theoretical
knowledge of the truth has been proved
to be insufficient for the saving of the
soul. It does not bring forth the fruits
of righteousness. A jealous regard for
what is termed theological truth often
accompanies a hatred of genuine truth as
made manifest in life. The darkest
chapters of history are burdened with
the record of crimes committed by
bigoted religionists.
The Pharisees claimed to be children of
Abraham and boasted of their possession
of the oracles of God. Yet these
advantages did not preserve them from
selfishness, maligny,
greed for gain and the basis hypocrisy.
They thought themselves the greatest
religionist of the world. But their soc
calledled orthodoxy led them to crucify
the Lord of glory.
And then she says this,
the same danger still exists.
Many take it for granted that they are
Christians simply because they subscribe
to certain theological tenants. I
believe marriage is between one man and
one woman. I am anti-abortion.
I believe. I believe. I believe. You can
even throw the Sabbath in there. I
believe the Sabbath.
Yet they have not brought the truth into
practical life. They have not believed
it and loved it. Therefore, they have
not received the power and grace that
come from sanctification of the truth.
And listen to how it is broken down in
this last sentence. You could believe
all you want to believe and say, "I got
the truth and I believe the truth." And
this goes if you're an Adventist or if
you're not an Adventist. You can believe
all day long. I have the truth. But I
want you to listen to this. Men may
profess faith in the truth, but if it
does not make them sincere,
kind,
patient, forbearing, heavenly minded, it
is a curse to its possessors
and through their influence, it is a
curse to the world.
The world is being cursed right now.
We can look around and see it.
And could it be could one of the reasons
be that the light that God put in the
world, the church that was to be an
example of love and mercy and kindness
and grace has said, "You know what?
We're tired of being the nice guys."
As if we ever were. We're tired of
playing nice.
We're tired of of of turning the other
cheek. We're tired We're tired of what
the opposition is doing.
You go low, we're going low. You get
angry, we're getting angry. You get mad,
we're getting mad.
You You You want vengeance, we're
getting vengeance. Could it be that the
world is is getting to be so dark right
now because the light that God put into
the world, that is to be through his
church,
is reflecting the very spirit of the
people that they claim
to despise
and hate.
May God open the eyes
of every Christian
who professes the name of Jesus
because there is a strong delusion
that has taken hold
of the Christian world
and that is the same delusion
that led to the fall of ancient Israel.
We can live and do and have whatever
kind of attitude we want. It doesn't
matter because when I said I accept you,
Lord,
I am unconditionally saved.
Doesn't matter what I do. Doesn't matter
what spirit I have. Doesn't matter what
spirit he has.
We're Christians
and we can curse you in the name of God.
We can hate you in the name of God and
we'll be satisfied.
We're tired and it's our turn to fight
you.
That is not Christianity. It is
something else, but it is not
Christianity. May the Lord open our
eyes. Heavenly Father,
we're asking in a special way, Lord. In
fact, we're asking, Lord, right now as I
pray,
Lord, I'm appealing to those that are
watching right now and those that will
watch. I'm appealing
that our hearts will be softened.
That the spirit of vengeance, the spirit
of anger,
the deception
that it doesn't matter what we do. It
doesn't matter. As long as we're doing
it in your name, it doesn't matter. We
can be angry in your name. We can hate
people in your name. We can despise
groups of people that we think aren't
following you in your name and and think
that we're being righteous. Lord, please
open our eyes and save us from that
deception.
Lord, I'm going to ask that that those
who are deciding to to to walk away from
this style of Christianity will put that
one in the chat saying, "Yes, Lord,
please remove that from me."
Put that one in the chat saying to the
Lord, "Lord, remove it from me.
Open my eyes to see
that false understandings of your
character and false understandings of
grace and false understandings of even
prophecy
can only lead to confusion and a foul
and unclean spirit. Lord, please
forgive us.
Forgive
us.
for not living out the things we confess
with our mouths
or for saying things with our mouths
that are not like you.
Please Lord, save your people. You have
people in every church. The churches are
not perfect, but you've got sincere
people in every church. May they hear
this call and come out of those systems
which are encouraging hate and anger and
vitriol and vengeance in the name of
Jesus before they get swept up and it is
too late. Please Lord, open the eyes of
your sincere Israelites.
May they hear your voice
and through this message may they follow
the lamb truly follow the lamb into all
truth is my prayer in Jesus name. Amen
and amen. I want to thank you all for
joining uh in this message today. May
God bless you. May God open your eyes.
May God speak to your heart and um and
may God draw you into all truth. We're
going to go ahead and put the the link
up for the uh afterlow discussion for
anyone who wants to join us. Uh click on
that link. We're going to fellowship.
We're going to talk about the Sabbath
school. We'll also talk about the the
the sermon and we'll get to fellowship,
share what we've learned from this.
And um uh if there's anyone that is
interested in Bible study, please reach
out to our Bible worker. If there's
anyone that is interested in baptism,
please reach out to our to our Bible
worker. We're going to put that address
up on the screen. If it's not up
already, it will go into the into the
chat. And please reach out and connect
with us. Let me see. I'm going to put
this up on the screen. Let's go to this
this slide, everyone. Um, you can see
here you can follow me on social media.
You can connect with LOC or you can
connect with a Bible worker um by
emailing Bible worker at living mana or
bibleworker at living matterana.urch.
You can even submit your prayer
requests. And uh that's it everyone. May
God bless you. May God keep you. May God
strengthen you. May God redeem you. May
God draw you closer to him. Amen. Amen.
Amen. God bless you.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]